<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory on Dr. Elliot</title>
    <link>https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory on Dr. Elliot</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:31:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Are Soft References?</title>
      <link>https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/softreferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:31:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/softreferences/</guid>
      <description>What Are Soft References? Soft references are a way to reference an object in Unreal Engine without forcing it to stay in memory. This can be incredibly useful in scenarios where you need to reference assets like textures, sounds, or even entire levels, but don’t want to load them into memory until absolutely necessary.&#xA;Why Use Soft References? Imagine your game has a massive library of assets. Loading everything at once would quickly consume your memory, leading to performance issues or, worse, crashing your game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working With Buffers</title>
      <link>https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/buffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 12:28:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrdrelliot.github.io/memory/buffers/</guid>
      <description>In Unreal Engine, buffers are simply containers of bytes that can store raw data using memory offsets. Understanding how to effectively manage these buffers is essential for tasks like serialization, deserialization, and data storage.&#xA;Raw C++ Buffer Management In raw C++, managing buffers and packing data requires manual handling of memory offsets. For example, consider the following code that packs several uint32_t values into a std::vector&amp;lt;std::byte&amp;gt; buffer:&#xA;#include &amp;lt;vector&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;cstdint&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;cstring&amp;gt; // For std::memcpy void PackData() { // Buffer to hold the packed data std::vector&amp;lt;std::byte&amp;gt; buffer; // Example data std::vector&amp;lt;uint32_t&amp;gt; data = { 1234, 5678, 91011 }; // Calculate the total size needed for the buffer size_t totalSize = data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
